Nothing escapes him.
Sherlock Holmes is a action, adventure, crime film directed by Guy Ritchie.
Eccentric consulting detective Sherlock Holmes and Doctor John Watson battle to bring
down a new nemesis and unravel a deadly plot that could destroy England.
Sherlock Holmes, played by Robert Downey Jr..
Dr. John Watson, played by Jude Law.
Irene Adler, played by Rachel McAdams.
Lord Henry Blackwood, played by Mark Strong.
Inspector Lestrade, played by Eddie Marsan.
Dredger, played by Robert Maillet.
Sherlock Holmes is a 2009 period mystery action film starring Robert Downey Jr.
as the character of the same name created by Sir Arthur Conan Doyle.
The film was directed by Guy Ritchie and produced by Joel
Silver, Lionel Wigram, Susan Downey, and Dan Lin.
The screenplay written by Michael Robert Johnson, Anthony Peckham, and Simon
Kinberg was developed from a story by Wigram and Johnson.
In addition to Downey as Holmes, Jude Law portrays Dr.
John Watson.
The film, set in 1890, follows eccentric detective Holmes and his companion Watson investigating
the crimes of Lord Blackwood, a mysticist who has seemingly risen from the dead.
Rachel McAdams stars as Holmes' former adversary Irene Adler and
Mark Strong portrays villain Lord Henry Blackwood.
Sherlock Holmes was wide released in theatres by Warner Bros.
Pictures on 25—26 December 2009.
It received mostly positive reviews from film critics, and grossed $525 million
worldwide, becoming the eighth-highest-grossing film of 2009.
Downey won the Golden Globe Award for Best Actor in a Musical or Comedy.
The film was also nominated for two Academy Awards, Best
Original Score and Best Art Direction.
A sequel, Sherlock Holmes: A Game of Shadows, was released in 2011, with a
third film in the works to be directed by Dexter Fletcher.
The film explores themes of london, england, based on novel
or book, detective, scotland yard, coffin.
The tone is mind_bending and intense.